《致命女人》前情提要
Previously on Why Women Kill...
她第三次被寄养家庭赶出来
She was kicked out of her third home
是因为她的养母指责她
because her foster mother accused her
试图勾引她的丈夫
of trying to seduce her husband.
一周后  那所房子被烧毁
A week later, that house burned down.
-你干了那些事  -他说的一个字
- You did those things? - You can't believe
-你都不能信  -老天  看着点
- a fucking word he says! - Jade, watch out!
我们给他注射前
Before we put him out,
他给你写了留言
he wrote you this note.
说这很重要
Said it was important.
-你跟他说了话吗  -没有
- Did you talk to him? - No.
泰勒来监狱看了我
Taylor came to see me in jail.
你这次把我害惨了
You really fucked me this time!
两位在俱乐部的会员资格被取消了
Your membership to the club has been revoked.
因为我生病了
It's because I'm ill.
是你干的
It was you.
你勾引了我的孩子
You seduced my child.
你真以为只是把你赶出乡村俱乐部
Do you think that I would be satisfied
我就会满意了吗
just getting you kicked out of a country club?
我才刚开始呢  贱人
I am just getting started, bitch.
爸总是说你报复心很重
Dad always said that you were vindictive.
我还是你妈妈
I am still your mother.
不  从现在起  你只是我曾认识的一个女人
No, from now on, you're just some lady that I used to know.
-你要开走吗  -先不走
- You pulling out? - Not yet.
我在等人
I'm waiting for someone.
我丈夫喜欢拿床头柜抽屉里
My husband likes to threaten me with a loaded gun
上了膛的枪威胁我
he keeps in his bedside drawer.
我们的女儿因我而死
Our daughter died because of me.
闯祸的是我
I'm the one who's responsible.
我最后一次和你丈夫上床
The last time I slept with your husband
是在你孩子死的那天
was the day your child died.
你们从前门进来的时候
While you were coming in the front door,
我绕着房子跑出去
I ran around the side of the house.
罗伯知道你没有关门吗
Did Rob know you had not closed the gate?
我那晚跟他打了电话  告诉了他
I called him that night and I told him.
有什么需要帮助的
What can I do for you?
我要买把枪
I need to buy a gun.
致命女人
第一季  第十集[季终]
你们觉得如何
So, what do you think?
很不错  建筑面积
It's impressive. Square footage?
五千
5,000.
左右
Give or take.
楼上有四个大卧室
Four big bedrooms upstairs.
有小孩吗
Got kids?
之前有个女儿
We had a little girl.
她叫艾米莉
Her name was Emily.
之前
Was?
我们失陪一下
Could you excuse us a moment?
你能别再告诉陌生人我们女儿死了吗
You've got to stop telling total strangers our daughter died.
他问了我一个问题
He asked me a question.
已经过了一年多了
It's been over a year.
要是我们一直谈论发生了什么
How are we gonna move forward in our lives
我们的生活要怎么翻篇
if we keep talking about what happened?
我都不知道我们在这做什么
I don't even understand what we're doing here.
我们现在的房子挺好的
The house we have now is fine.
有太多回忆
It's got too many memories.
我们需要一个崭新的开始
We need a fresh start.
这可能对我们来说是好事
I mean, this could be good for us.
你不想找到再次幸福的办法吗
Don't you want to find a way to be happy again?
我当然想了
Of course I do.
那就让我为你买下这房子
Well, then let me buy this for you.
如果你这么做  我就会每天
If you do that, I'll spend every day
都努力让笑容重回你的脸上
just trying to put the smile back on your face.
我当初爱上的那个笑容
The one I fell in love with.
我想我们是可以在这找到幸福
I guess we could be happy here.
当然可以
Of course we can.
给我展示下我爱的那个笑容
Now where's that smile I love?
我昨天买了把枪
I bought a gun yesterday.
什么
What?
我从我的癌症医生那看完病后
I'd left an appointment at my cancer doctors,
我经过了一家超可爱的枪支商店
and I passed the most adorable gun shop.
我买了一把小左轮手枪
And I bought this little revolver.
我们要枪做什么
Why do we need a gun?
最近附近有发生盗窃
There have been robberies in the neighborhood.
街角的贝茨夫人
Mrs. Betz on the corner?
一个小偷砸碎了她家窗户  闯进去
Some thief smashed her window, reached in,
从她的茶几上拿走了她新买的包
and took her new purse right off her end table.
-我有见过她吗  -总之
- Have I met her? - Anyway,
我感觉不太安全
I don't feel safe.
所以我买了这把枪  放在了这里
So I got this gun, and I'm storing it here.
已经装了子弹
And I've already put in the bullets.
你给枪上膛了
You're keeping the gun loaded?
如果有人攻击我们
If someone attacks us,
我们应该不想浪费时间去找子弹  对吗
I don't think we'd want to waste time looking for bullets. Do you?
这是条和谐的街道
This is a nice street.
我们不会出什么坏事的
Nothing bad is going to happen to us.
世事难料
You never know.
所以...
So...
你们觉得怎么样
what do you think?
你带我们来真是太对了
You were right to bring us here.
这房子能创造太多可能性了
So many possibilities.
对  房子格局还不错
Yes, the floor plan's good,
但墙上的颜色真是...
but really, the color of the walls...
在我们继续之前
Before we go any further,
法律强制我揭露这里发生过谋杀
state lawcompels me to disclose that a murder took place here.
有人在这栋房子里被杀了吗
Someone was murdered in this house?
是粉刷匠吗
Was it the decorator?
萨蒙妮
Simone!
娜奥米
Naomi!
我看见你的车在外面
I saw your car out front.
快告诉我你们要把这里买下来
Tell me that you are buying this place.
我就住在一个街区外
I live a block away.
我们能成为邻居了
We would be neighbors.
卡尔  这是我乡村俱乐部的朋友娜奥米
Karl, this is my friend Naomi from the country club.
你就是那个我一直听说的时髦新男友吧
You must be the dashing new boyfriend I keep hearing about.
不仅仅是男友
Not just the boyfriend.
-更进一步了  -不会吧
- I've, uh, been promoted. - Stop.
你们订婚了
You're engaged?
那你们现在肯定需要一所更大的房子了
Oh, well, now you definitely need a bigger house.
-这个年轻帅小伙是谁啊  -汤米
- And who's this charming young man? - Tommy.
这是我儿子汤米
This is my son Tommy.
汤米  这是萨蒙妮
Tommy, this is Simone.
你真漂亮
You're pretty.
小孩子嘴最甜了
Kids say the cutest things.
小伙子别垂涎了  她名花有主了
Oh, hands off, young man. She's spoken for.
萨蒙妮  拜托你们一定要买下这房子
Oh, Simone, please tell me you'll take the house.
我太想你搬过来住了
I'd absolutely kill to have you here.
那一定会很有趣  不是吗
Oh, it would be fun, wouldn't it?
住在我最好朋友的家附近
Being close to my best friend.
萨蒙妮
Simone!
你没事吧
Are you all right?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
发生什么了
What happened?
我妈妈想杀了你
My mother tried to kill you.
什么
What?
我的天  她还活着吗
Oh, my God, is she alive?
汤米
Tommy.
快叫医生
Someone call a doctor!
-好  -还有警察
- Okay. - And the police!
那么...你们觉得怎么样
So... what do you think?
我觉得...我很喜欢  就这么定了吧
I mean... I love it. I say, let's do it.
-什么  -我想买这栋房子
- What? - I want to buy this house.
我能跟我丈夫私下商量一下吗
Can I talk with my husband for a moment in private, please?
慢慢来
Take your time.
-怎么了  -老兄  你疯了吗
- What? - Dude, are you crazy?
你疯...你没看到那个泳池吗
Are you cra...? Did you not see that pool?
而且厨房很大
And that kitchen is huge.
对  但是需要彻底重新装修  我们没那么多钱
Yeah, and it needs a complete remodel. We can't afford that.
别担心钱的事  好吗
D-Don't worry about the money, all right?
我的事业快起飞了
My career is taking off.
《昨日珍妮》的评论爆了
The reviews for Jenny from Yesterday are through the roof.
我知道  但即便如此还是太冒险了
Yeah, I know, but even so, it's still risky.
冒险  你听听你自己说的话
Risky? Are you hearing yourself right now?
-你知道你听起来像谁吗  -谁
- Do you know who you sound like? - Who?
像我  当我们谈开放婚姻的时候
Me... when we were talking about having an open marriage?
好吧  这不是一回事
Okay, that's not the same thing.
不  我...我当时很紧张
No. I was... I was nervous.
我不确定我们能否适应  但你说服了我
I was unsure that we could make it work, but you convinced me.
现在我们的日子过得多刺激呀
And now our life is so much more exciting for it.
你想想如果有了这厨房  我们的日子
Now think about how much even more exciting our life would be
能刺激到什么程度  对吧
with that fucking kitchen, right?
宝贝  你感冒还没好吗
Oh, sweetie, you still have that cold?
好了  我没事  我没事
It's fine. I'm good. I'm good.
泰勒  相信我
Just, Taylor, trust me.
好吗  相信我
Okay? Believe in me.
我发誓我不会让你失望的
I promise you I will not let you down.
慢点
Take it slow.
天啊  全身都痛
God, everything hurts.
好吧  有件事能让你舒服些
Well, here's something to ease the pain.
我回了趟家  所有洁德的东西都没了
I went by the house. All of Jade's stuff is gone.
动作真快
That was fast.
对  她知道我们知道她干了什么
Yeah. Well, she knows we're onto her.
她总不能待在那等警察来抓她吧
She can't just stick around, waiting for the cops to show up.
说到房子
Oh, speaking of the house,
我有个东西给你
I, uh, got you a little something.
一张名片吗
A business card?
对  拉马尔的房产经纪人
Yeah. For Lamar's realtor.
如果你同意的话我想把房子卖了
If it's okay with you, I want to sell the house.
真的吗
Really?
对  感觉
Yeah, it just feels like
我们的每个错误决定都能追溯到
every wrong turn we've made can be traced back
我让你买房子的那一刻
to the moment where I talked you into buying it.
没有房子
No house...
就不会遇见洁德
wouldn't have met Jade.
没有洁德  不会毒瘾复发
No Jade, no relapse.
我们会少很多压力
I mean, we'd lose a lot of stress.
光是不还房贷就轻松很多
The mortgage payments alone.
看看那笑容
Look at that smile.
好吧  那我们要降级到什么
All right. So how much downsizing are we up for?
联排别墅  公寓
Townhouse? Condo?
去他的  我们干脆买块地
Fuck it. Let's just buy a field.
扎个帐篷
We can pitch a tent.
棒极了
Love it.
田野上的帐篷  美梦成真了
Tent in a field. We'd be living the dream.
而且搬家最棒的地方在于  洁德找不到我们
And the best part about moving... Jade won't be able to find us.
你觉得她去哪了
Where do you think she went?
不知道
I don't know.
最好现在已经千里之外了
Let's just hope she's a thousand miles away by now.
给我的杜克
谁是杜克
Who's Duke?
我祖父
My grandfather.
祖母苏在第一年结婚纪念日是送给他的
Grammy Sue gave that to him for their first wedding anniversary.
他每天都戴  却从未上过发条
He wore it every day, but he never wound it.
他总说
He always used to say that
"当我遇见小苏时  仿佛时间都静止了"
"When I met my Susie, it was like time stood still."
真甜蜜
Sweet.
给你35
Give you 35.
三千五吗
Hundred?
不  35块
No. Dollars.
它比那值钱多了
It's worth much more than that.
从情感的角度来说  也许吧
Sentimental-wise, maybe.
但想兑现  就值35
Cash-wise, it's worth $35.
-我需要更多  -好吧
- Well, I need more. - All right.
为你这故事我再添五块
I'll throw in an extra five for the story.
因为我喜欢你的脸
And 'cause I like your... face.
不如一千吧
How about a grand?
我没那么喜欢你的脸
I don't like your face that much.
好吧  那就几百块
Okay, well, then a couple hundred.
-亲爱的  我说了  -拜托
- Honey, I told you... - Please.
你不知道我最近经历了什么
You don't understand what I've been through lately.
我失去了一切  我只需要一点
I've lost everything, and I just need a little...
你需要的是收起那假惺惺的眼泪
What you need is to give the waterworks a rest.
我开价了  你爱要不要
I made you my offer, so either take it
不要出去
or get the hell out.
搞什么  我报警了
The fuck?! I'm calling the cops!
嗯  这话我听得多了
Yeah, I get that a lot.
贝丝·安
Beth Ann.
早上好  玛丽  我希望我没打扰你
Morning, Mary. I hope I'm not interrupting?
不  完全没有  拉尔夫刚去上班
No, not at all. Ralph just left for work.
我知道  我特地等他走了才来
I know. I waited for him to go.
我要和你私下谈谈
I need to speak to you privately.
-怎么了  -我想到了一个
- What's going on? - I've thought of a way
能解决我们各自婚姻问题的方法
to solve our respective marital difficulties.
真的吗
You have?
我想到了如何杀死我们丈夫的主意
I've come up with a plan on how to kill our husbands.
请我进屋吧
Please invite me in.
这种事我们该边喝咖啡边聊
This is the sort of thing we should discuss over coffee.
这就是计划
That's the plan.
有什么想法吗
Any thoughts?
太疯狂了
It's crazy.
-我们会被抓的  -不会
- We'd never get away with it. - But we would.
你想想  严格来说
Think about it. Technically speaking,
我们没做任何违法的事
we wouldn't be doing anything illegal.
那我们怎么知道罗伯和拉尔夫
How could we be sure that Rob and Ralph
会上这个当呢
would even swallow the bait?
这就是这个计划的精妙之处
That's the beauty of the plan.
这计划完全是为
It's tailor-made to fit
他们糟糕透顶的性格量身定做
their horribly predictable personalities.
如果有人发现我们做了什么怎么办
What if someone discovers what we've done?
我没打算告诉别人
I don't plan on telling anyone.
你呢
Do you?
我不知道
I don't know.
拉尔夫是该死
Ralph deserves to die.
罗伯让你经受了那么多苦楚
And... after everything Rob's put you through,
他也一样坏
he's just as bad.
但《圣经》说
But the Bible says,
"不可杀人"
"Thou shalt not kill."
上帝也许不会理解
God might not understand.
也许不会
Maybe not.
但我肯定上帝的妻子会
But I'm sure God's wife will.
那么  你怎么说
Now, what do you say?
汤米
Oh. Tommy.
你看上去见到我很惊讶
You seem surprised to see me.
我们现在是社交瘟疫  人人避之
Well, we're such social pariahs these days,
我见到谁都很惊讶
I'm surprised to see anyone.
现在要是有耶和华见证人上门
At this point, I'd roll out the red carpet
我都要铺红毯了
for a Jehovah's Witness.
你感觉如何
How are you feeling?
很好
Delightful.
萨蒙妮在厨房里
Simone's in the kitchen.
你妈妈的物理治疗怎么样
How is your mother's physical therapy going?
好点了
Better.
她今天走了几步
She took a few steps today.
我还是觉得你应该提起诉讼
I still think that you should have pressed charges.
她说她失去了对车的控制
She said she lost control of the car.
我选择相信她
I choose to believe her.
其他人都不信
Nobody else does.
她在乡村俱乐部的所有朋友
All of her friends at the country club,
那些让她游说敌对你和卡尔的人
the ones that she turned against you and Karl,
最终都发现我妈才是疯子  都抛弃了她
they finally found out Mom's crazy and they dropped her.
可怜的娜奥米
Oh. Poor Naomi.
"Poor Naomi"?
拜托
Come on.
你肯定还是觉得有点高兴吧
You must be a little pleased.
我想成为的那种女人
The woman I'm trying to become
绝对不会从这种事情中获得愉悦
would draw no satisfaction from this at all.
幸运的是  我还没成为那种女人呢
Fortunately, I'm not that woman just yet.
我在想要取消去巴黎的旅行
I'm thinking about canceling my trip to Paris.
你不能让因为愧对妈妈而影响行程
You can't let your mother guilt you into staying.
我留下来是为你  而不是为她
I'd be staying for you, not her.
卡尔越来越病重了  对吧
Karl's getting worse, isn't he?
我会好好照料他的
I'll take good care of him.
那谁来照料你呢
But who will take care of you?
我没事的
I'll be fine.
你应该走了
Oh, you should go.
卡尔有医生的预约
Karl has a doctor's appointment.
我很抱歉我们的关系造成了这样的丑闻
I'm sorry our relationship caused such a scandal.
我试着告诉别人是我追的你
I try to tell people I'm the one who pursued you,
但他们都不愿意相信这是我的错
but they refuse to believe it was my fault.
你这么说好像我们做了什么该后悔的事
You say that like we did something we should regret.
我没有后悔过我们相处的任何时刻
I don't regret one moment we shared.
走吧
Now go.
去享受你人生最棒的一个夏天吧
Have the most wonderful summer of your life.
学学美术  喝点红酒
Study art. Drink wine.
时不时地想想我
Think of me every now and then.
我会一直想着你的
I'll think of you constantly.
我爱你
I love you.
你以后还会对别的女人说这句话
I won't be the last woman you say that to.
但我很自豪能成为第一个
But I'm proud to be the first.
六个月后
我拿来了
Here it is.
你确定你想把它卖掉吗
Now, you're sure you want to part with this?
我很想留下
Oh, I'd love to keep it,
但事实上  我们需要钱
but the truth is, we need the money.
萨蒙妮  事情已经坏到这个地步了吗
Simone, are things really as bad as all that?
画廊倒了后  我们就没有医保了
Once the art gallery went under, we lost our health insurance.
卡尔的医疗账单数额高得吓人
And Karl's medical bills have been outrageous.
我能做点什么吗
Is there anything I can do?
你可以再买一幅画
You could buy another painting.
或许你想让我的画像挂在你家客厅里
Perhaps you'd like to have me hanging in your living room?
不如我为这幅画再多付你一千美元吧
Why don't I just pay you another thousand for this one?
你真是个好人
That's very kind.
但又有点侮辱人
And somewhat insulting.
保重  科尔
Take care, Cole.
萨蒙妮
Simone?
怎么了  卡尔
Yes, Karl?
我需要你
I need you.
你还好吗
Is everything okay?
是的  就是想把自己打扮得可以见人
Yes, I'm just trying to make myself presentable.
能帮我擦脖子吗
Would you do my neck?
当然了
Oh, of course.
你要去哪里吗
Are you going somewhere?
我的支持小组的蒂姆刚刚出院
Tim from my support group's just got out of hospital.
哈罗德要给他办个早午餐会
Harold's holding a brunch in his honor.
那真是太好了
Oh, that should be nice.
你没尝过他的厨艺
You haven't tasted his cooking.
我确定在上甜点之前我们就会回急救室了
I'm sure we'll all be back in the emergency room by dessert.
你真贱
You are such a bitch.
希望如此
I should hope so.
毕竟我师从大师
I did study with a master.
我刚听到了门铃
Oh, I heard the doorbell.
是谁啊
Who was it?
科尔来拿画了
Cole stopped by to pick up the painting.
天哪  我感到好内疚
Oh, Lord, I feel so dreadful about that.
我知道你有多喜欢那幅画
I-I know how much you love that piece.
没关系
It's okay.
至少现在能还抵押贷款了
At least we can pay the mortgage now.
至少能还掉大部分
Or most of it.
我很抱...我很抱歉
I am s... I am so sorry.
别说了
Stop it.
我们没事
We are fine.
你说得对
Uh, you are right.
我们是两个...
We are, uh, two...
女贱神
bitch goddesses.
我们是不会输的
And we will not be defeated.
转过去
Now turn.
今早出门前我是怎么跟你们交代的
What did I tell all you this morning before we left the house?
我是怎么说的
Huh? What did I say?
不要给你丢人现眼
Not to embarrass you.
都是因为你们几个小鬼对那个倒霉的假人模特干的好事
I can never go back to that store ever again
我被那家商店永久拉黑了
because of what you little freaks did to that poor mannequin.
快进屋
Go inside.
还愣着干嘛
Now!
你好
Hello.
不知你是否还记得我
I'm not sure if you remember who I am.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
那你能告诉我你是谁吗
Can you tell me who you are?
我们先把话说明  亲爱的
Let's start with the headline, hon.
我不是罗伯·斯坦顿的老婆
I'm not Rob Stanton's wife.
进来吧
Come on in.
是时候告诉你真相了
I think it's time someone told you the truth.
谢谢你  拉马尔
Thank you, Lamar.
你的支持对我很重要
Your support means a lot.
好的  没问题
Yeah. Yeah.
待我戒毒成功归来  我们再会
I will see you on the other side, man.
好的  挂了
Okay. Bye.
在我戒毒期间你要如何打发无聊时光呢
So, how you gonna stay busy while I'm at rehab?
我猜你会说  找女伴聊以自慰
Guessing the short answer is "girls, girls, girls"?
既然你提到这点
Well, funny you should mention that.
或许我们可以重新考虑
I thought maybe we could rethink
是否仍想继续进行开放式婚姻
the whole open marriage thing.
-真的吗  -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
我们应该多花点时间在彼此身上
You know, we should focus on us for a while.
可以试下婚姻咨询
Go to therapy.
三人不欢
And three's a crowd.
尤其是在做婚姻咨询时
Especially in couples counseling.
好吧
Okay.
你不喜欢这个主意吗
What, you don't like that idea?
我喜欢  只是...
No. It's just...
显然你的性向对你很重要
I mean, obviously, your sexuality is really important.
我不想让你被迫舍弃部分自我
And... I just don't want you to have to give any part of that up.
是对我确实很重要
It is important to me.
但正如我常说的那样
But like I've always said,
我只愿与你共度余生
my love story is with you.
若把你与几个炮友相比  我总会选择你
And I would choose you over a few casual hookups any day of the week.
就只是你和我了吗
It would just be you and me?
不再有其他人
Forsaking all others?
至死不渝
Till death do us part.
我们是不是突然变成保守派了
Did we just become Republicans?
好像是的
I think we did.
赫克托  你来了
Hector, hi.
快请进
Come on in.
卡尔在午睡  要不我去把他叫醒
Karl is taking a nap. Should I wake him?
不用了  实际上...
Uh, no. Actually, uh,
我是来找你的
I'm here to see you.
发生了什么事
Oh. What's going on?
还记得上周日  我带卡尔去哈罗德的早午餐会吗
Remember last Sunday, when I took Karl to that brunch at Harold's?
记得  谢谢你载他过去
Yes. Thank you for driving him.
哈罗德今天打给我了
So, Harold called me today.
他猜测卡尔从他的药柜里偷了些药片
He thinks Karl stole some pills from his medicine cabinet.
哪类药片
What kind of pills?
安眠药
Sleeping pills.
两周前我们在比利家打桥牌时
And the same thing happened two weeks ago
也发生了同样的事
when we went to Billy's for bridge.
这样啊
I see.
卡尔表面上故作坚强
Karl puts on a brave face,
但我知道他内心有多难过
but I know how depressed he's been.
我非常担心他
And I'm just so worried.
你确实应该告诉我这些事
You did the right thing telling me.
萨蒙妮  把这压力丢给你我非常过意不去
Simone, I'm so sorry to dump this on you.
但他向来只听得进你的话
But you've always been the only one who can get through to him.
我会处理的
I will take care of it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你来誊写那封信
So, while you copy the letter in your handwriting,
我去楼上帮你打包衣物
I'll be upstairs cleaning out your closet.
你说过拉尔夫大概六点四十五分到家  对吗
You said Ralph gets home around 6:45?
有时六点半就回来了
Sometimes as early as 6:30.
罗伯六点十五分左右到家  现在已经快五点了
Rob gets home around 6:15, and it's almost 5:00.
我们得抓紧时间
We need to get cracking.
贝丝·安
Beth Ann?
当拉尔夫读到这封信时...
When Ralph reads this...
他一定会怒不可遏
he will absolutely get violent.
希望如此
We can only hope.
亲爱的拉尔夫
亲爱的拉尔夫  我这段时间
过得很不快乐
...离开你
我爱上了另一个人
我去农贸市场
I'm going to the farmers market.
穿这身去吗
Wearing that?
虽然我得和一群土气主妇一起购物
Well, just because I have to shop with the frumps
但不代表我就得打扮得像她们一样
doesn't mean I have to dress like them.
要帮你带点什么吗
Can I get you anything?
还真有
Oh, yes, actually, um,
我需要一百颗安眠药
I could use a hundred sleeping pills
替换你从我梳妆台拿走的那些
to replace the ones you took out of my dresser.
你发现了
You noticed.
还真快
That was fast.
去年你生我的气
Yes, last year you were angry with me
因为我没服下足以自杀的药量
because I didn't take enough pills to kill myself,
现在你却一颗都不让我吃
and now you won't let me have any.
你得选定一种策略并坚持到底啊  亲爱的
You need to choose a policy and stick to it, my girl.
我们必须和这疾病作斗争  绝不能屈服
We have to fight this disease. We can't give into it.
你真的忘了
Have you really forgotten
我上次肺炎发作有多严重了吗
how bad my last bout of pneumonia was?
我还以为自己走不出医院了
I wasn't sure I was leaving the hospital.
但你康复了  现在好好的
But you did, and now you're fine.
亲爱的  我一点都不好
Darling, I'm not fine.
如果我的T细胞是人
If my T cells were people,
我当时组局打桥牌的人都凑不够
I couldn't get up a bridge game,
所以拜托你把药还给我
so please, please give me the pills back.
我已经冲下水槽了
I already washed them down the sink.
那你只是逼我采取更可怕的方法
Well, then, you'll just force me to do something more gruesome.
上吊或一枪爆头
So, hang myself or blow my brains out.
你来选
You choose.
我发誓  如果你自杀导致破相
So help me, if you do anything disfiguring,
我一定会给你办开棺葬礼
I will give you an open-casket funeral
不帮你化妆  也不开荧光灯美颜
with no makeup and fluorescent lighting.
天啊
Dear God,
我娶的是魔鬼本人呢
I married the devil herself.
我知道我们不会永远在一起
Oh, I know we won't be together always,
但为何要减少我们能共度的时光呢
but why subtract even a day we could share?
好吧  好吧
Fine. Fine.
你赢了
You win.
其实我下午要去参加一个生日派对
Actually, um, I'm going to a birthday party this afternoon.
或许你可以陪我去
Maybe you'd like to join me.
是吉米·洛夫特斯生日
It's for Jimmy Loftus.
我很想再见到他  他总能逗我开心
Oh, I'd love to see him again. He's always a hoot.
他还好吗
How is he doing?
恐怕不太好
Well, I'm afraid he's had a bit of a setback.
他住院了
He's in the hospital.
不
Oh, no.
派对在他病房里举行
Yes, the party's in his room.
你要是能去  一定会帮他振作精神
If you come, I'm sure it would lift his spirits.
我很想去
I'd love to come.
我很开心
I'm so glad.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
-好了  -亲爱的
- All right. - Honey...
过来抱下
Come here, you.
我的肋骨
my ribs.
-抱歉  -不  没事
- I'm sorry. - No, no. No, no.
别停  继续抱  我能受得了
Don't stop, don't stop. I can take it.
你不是说洁德离开时把狗也带走了吗
I thought you said Jade took the dog when she left.
是的
She did.
-你在这里做什么  -做晚饭
- What are you doing here? - I'm making dinner.
好吧
Okay.
你得立刻离开
I think you need to leave.
我知道之前闹得有点不愉快
I know things got a little funky for a minute there,
但我们没理由不可以
but there's no reason that we can't go back
回到从前那样
to the way we were before.
有很多理由不可以
Oh, I think there are a lot of reasons.
-是的  洁德  请你...  -她不叫洁德
- Yeah, Jade, please... - Her name's not Jade.
谁在乎啊
Who cares?
我就不能重塑自我吗
Am I not allowed to reinvent myself?
我操
I mean, fuck.
听我说  我们都先冷静下来
Okay, you know what, let's just all settle down.
你们表现得好像一切都是我的错  不是的
You guys act like everything that happened is my fault; it's not.
我本来可以去欧洲的
I could have gone to Europe,
但你求我留下来
but you begged me to stay.
你假装爱我
You pretended to love me,
而你答应你会永远照顾我
and you promised that you would always take care of me.
这不公平
It's not fair.
你说得对
You're right.
你说得对  这不公平
You're right, it's not fair.
好了  别说了
Okay, just stop.
你说的话我一个字都不信
I don't believe one thing about you.
更别说你的眼泪了
Least of all your tears.
我没假装爱你  我是真的爱你
I didn't pretend to love you, I did.
但那是因为我不知道你的真面目
But that's because I didn't know who you really are.
你试图骗我们
You tried to trick us.
你玩弄了我们  但是你输了
You played us, and you lost.
都结束了
It's done.
现在滚吧
Now get out.
我会走的...
I'll go...
但你先得给我钱
but you have to pay me first.
你觉得你能敲诈我们
You think you can shake us down?
-宝贝  -重新开始是需要钱的
- Honey. - It costs money to start over.
我们不会帮助和教唆罪犯的
We're not aiding and abetting a criminal.
是你们欠我的
You owe me.
伊莱的稿子买了一百万美元
Eli sold our script for a million dollars.
给我一万  我就走
Give me ten grand, and I'll go.
我不会给你钱让你走的  我会直接报警
I'm not gonna pay you to leave. I'm just gonna call the cops.
这样吧  我们冷静一下
All right, you know what, let's just hold on a second.
好吗  你知道我接下来要干什么吗
Okay? You know what I'm gonna do?
我会跟她谈谈  我们会解决这个问题的
I'm gonna go talk to her. We're gonna work this out.
我觉得虽然你经历了这么多
I mean, after all, you've been through a lot,
但你不是个坏人
but you're not a bad person.
是吧  不是的吧  好的
Right? No, no, okay.
你怎么能让我一个人
How could you leave me alone
面对那个神经病
with that psychopath?
我找不到我的手机了
I can't find my fucking phone.
放在哪里了
Where is it?
烟雾报警器
Smoke alarm.
她要烧了房子
She's burning down the goddamn house.
所以吉米预计还能活多久
So what, exactly, is Jimmy's prognosis?
不管怎么样  这是场派对
Well, whatever it is, this is a party,
所以你要努力微笑
so please try to smile.
亲爱的  我能笑着面对一切
Darling, I can smile through anything.
卡尔  萨蒙妮 你们来了
Karl, Simone, you made it.
你好  让我们过去
Hello, hello. Oh, let us through,
我们想看看小寿星
we want to see the birthday boy.
生日快乐
吉米  看看是谁来了
Jimmy, look who's here.
是卡尔和萨蒙妮
It's Karl and Simone.
生日快乐  吉米
Happy birthday, Jimmy.
你该看看萨蒙妮穿着什么
And you should see what Simone is wearing.
我觉得是老佛爷
I think it's Lagerfeld.
卡尔  萨蒙妮
Karl, Simone,
我想给你们介绍一下吉米的妈妈和他的姐姐泰蕊
I wanted you to meet Jimmy's mom and his sister Terry.
她们刚刚从爱荷华州赶来
They just got in from Iowa.
很高兴认识你们
It is so lovely to meet you both.
看到吉米身边有这么一群有爱的朋友
I can't tell you how comforting it's been
别提我有多欣慰了
to find Jimmy here surrounded by such loving friends.
你还没有完全见识到呢  亲爱的
Oh, you ain't seen nothing yet, honey.
我做了我最拿手的胡萝卜蛋糕
I made my famous carrot cake.
吉米先生  你一定得来一块
You are having a piece, Mr. Jim,
哪怕得把它挤成泥从你的胳膊输进去
even if they have to puree it and drip it into your arm.
他能听到我们说话吗
Can he hear us?
当然能
Of course he can.
既然大家都到了  那该唱歌了
Everyone's here now. Time to sing.
开始
Here we go.
*祝你生日快乐*
* Happy birthday to you *
*生日快乐  亲爱的吉米*
* Happy birthday, dear Jimmy *
*祝你生日快乐*
*Happy birthday to you*
我不明白他怎么能恶化得这么快
I don't understand how he got so sick so quickly.
这病就是这样的
This is the disease.
我看着它发生在克莱夫  哈利
I've watched it happen to Clive, to Harry,
阿里斯特的身上...
to Alistair...
这真的很可怕
It's just horrifying.
你知道吗  之前吉米告诉我
You know, Jimmy once told me
他很害怕就这样结束一生
he was scared of ending up like this.
全身插满管子  耗着等死
Connected to tubes, wasting away.
但是现在他还是变成了这样
But here he is.
你知道我之后会也会这样的
You know what I'm driving at.
你病得没那么厉害
You're not that sick.
迟早会的
Yet.
但我们已经能看到我的未来了
But we've seen my future.
我很想选择继续活着
I would rather choose life,
但活着...
but life is...
已经选不了了
...off the table.
我唯一能选的就是
The only thing I can choose is
什么时候死去...
when to die and...
以及怎么死去
how.
我今天带你来这里
I brought you here today
是因为我需要你能理解
because I needed you to understand.
你能吗
Do you?
谢谢你
Thank you.
罗伯
Rob.
你回来了
You're home.
而且很饿  晚饭做好了吗
And starving. Is dinner ready?
今天太忙了
The day got away from me.
我只能点了中餐外卖
I had to order Chinese takeout.
但今天是周四
But it's Thursday.
我本来很期待烘肉卷的
I was looking forward to meatloaf.
我给你调了马天尼  但愿能让你开心点
If it helps, I made you a shaker of martinis.
等外卖的时候你可以喝几杯
You could have a few while we wait.
这还差不多
Now you're talkin'.
谢了
Thanks.
你是泰勒·哈丁吗
Are you Taylor Harding?
是的  你们来得好快  进来吧
Yeah. Wow, you got here fast. Come on in.
伊莱  警察来了
Eli, the police are here.
这么快
Already?
不好意思  你们在等我们吗
I'm sorry, were you expecting us?
是的  我们报警有人非法闯入
Yeah, we reported a break-in.
十分钟前刚报的警
That was, like, ten minutes ago.
我们不是为非法闯入而来的
We're not here about any break-in.
我们是来谈杜克·莱利的
We came to talk about Duke Riley.
杜克怎么了
What about Duke?
六周前你向警方报案
You filed a police report six weeks ago
指控他袭击
accusing him of assault.
-是的  -然后四天前
- Yes. - And then four days ago,
你交了他的保释金
you posted his bail.
是的  为什么问这个
I did. Why are you asking?
杜克·莱利昨天被杀害了
Duke Riley was murdered yesterday.
他的房东在公寓里发现了他的尸体
His landlord found his body in his apartment.
他身上有多处刺伤
He had been repeatedly stabbed.
你知道可能是谁干的吗
Do you have any idea who might have done this?
大概知道
I think we do.
这是我的第三杯了
Whoa, this'll be my third one.
谁在数呢
Oh, who's counting?
斯坦顿夫人  你是想灌醉我吗
Mrs. Stanton, are you trying to get me drunk?
我只是想让你放松下来
I just wanted you to be relaxed
这样我们就可以聊聊了
so we could have a little chat.
聊什么
About what?
聊我们女儿死的那天
About the day our daughter died.
用这个就行吗
This will do it?
是的  一剂就行
Yes, just the one dose.
你不会感到任何痛苦  只会...睡过去
And you won't feel any pain, you'll just... sleep?
据说是的
So I'm told.
你确定不要赫克托来陪你吗
Are you sure you don't want Hector here?
不用  我们  我们已经道过别了
No, no. We've, um, we've said our goodbyes.
他也想来的  但是
I-I mean, he wanted to be here, but...
他太情绪化了
well, he's so bloody emotional.
一提到我的死  他就像汽车警报一样嚎啕大哭
The mere mention of my death, he starts wailing like a car alarm.
留点口德  他爱你
Be nice. He loves you.
我知道
I know.
不过说实话
But to be honest, uh,
我只想要我们两个人
I just wanted it to be the two of us.
你值得比我更多的
You deserve to have more than just me.
你应该举办一个盛大的派对来送行
You should have a huge, glorious party to send you off.
你就是一个盛大的派对  无需他人
You are a glorious party, all by yourself.
第一眼看到你时
I knew that the first moment
我就知道了
I laid eyes on you.
你永远都是我一生的挚爱
You'll always be the love of my life.
接下来怎么办呢
So, what happens now?
首先  我
Well, uh, firstly, I...
我想让你换上我在威尼斯给你买的
I'd like you to change into the red gown
那件红色礼服
I bought you in Venice.
这件有什么不好吗
What's wrong with this one?
我喜欢红色那件
I prefer the red.
好吧
All right.
但这是我最后一次让你给我挑衣服了
But this is the last time I'll let you edit my wardrobe.
换好衣服后  到客厅来
When you've changed, come down to the living room.
我有个惊喜给你
I have a nice surprise for you.
我不想聊艾米莉
I don't want to talk about Emily.
我想聊  最近我一直在想那天的事
Well, I do. I've been thinking about that day a lot lately.
我想起了一件事
And I've remembered something.
什么事
What's that?
把垃圾桶拖进来后
I absolutely locked the gate
我绝对把大门锁上了
after I brought in the trash can.
你肯定是没锁
Well, you must not have.
不然艾米莉是怎么跑到街上去的
How else did Emily get out into the street?
也许你可以想出另一种解释
Perhaps you could come up with another explanation.
想想
Think.
我感觉不舒服
I'm not feeling well.
亲爱的
My darling.
你无法想象这一刻对我有多重要
You can't possibly imagine how important this moment is to me.
拜托
Please.
那天发生了什么你没告诉我的事吗
Did anything happen that day you haven't told me?
没有
No.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢什么
For what?
你让这一切变得简单多了
You've made this all so much easier.
显然她很危险
Well, she's obviously dangerous.
在我们找到她之前  也许你们应该考虑
You might want to think about staying someplace
换个地方住几天
for a few days until we locate her.
我们今晚就去住酒店
We'll check into a hotel tonight.
在你们离开前  我们安排一辆警车在外面守着
And we'll put a car on the street outside until you leave.
别担心  我们不会放她进来的
Don't worry. She won't get past us.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Night.
好吧  我只想在警探面前保持镇静
Okay, I was trying to be cool in front of the detectives,
但是  我的天呐  洁德杀了杜克
but oh, my God, Jade killed Duke.
-我知道  我知道  -等下
- I know. I know. - Wait,
你觉得她真的会回来吗
do you think she's actually gonna come back here?
我们不能坐以待毙
We can't stick around long enough to find out.
-那那只狗怎么办  -带它一起走
- What about the dog? - We'll take it with us.
你先喂它  我去收拾东西
You feed her first, I'll go start packing.
-好  过来  茶杯  -好了
- Okay. All right. Come on, Teacup. - Okay.
玛丽  我回来了
Mary, I'm home.
给我拿啤酒
Bring me a beer!
这次用马克杯装
And I want it in a mug this time.
玛丽
Mary?
亲爱的拉尔夫  我已经不开心很久了
Dearest Ralph. I haven't been happy for quite some time.
但那并非我决定要离开你的原因
But that's not why I've decided to leave you.
我遇到了一个人  一个让我感到幸福的男人
I've met someone else. A man who makes me happy.
所以我要离开你  投向罗伯·斯坦顿的怀抱
So I'm leaving you for Rob Stanton.
你永远都无法像他那样爱我
He loves me in a way you never could.
你的前妻  玛丽
Your ex-wife, Mary.
妈的
Shit.
你不接吗
Aren't you gonna get that?
一定是打错了
Must have been a wrong number.
中餐什么时候能送到  我饿了
Well, when's the Chinese food getting here? I'm hungry.
肯定很快就能到了
I'm sure it'll arrive any second.
看见没
See?
等下
Wait.
你确定是送餐的人吗  他听起来很愤怒
Are you sure that's the delivery guy? He sounds angry.
不然还能是谁
Who else could it be?
你太美了
You are so beautiful.
你也很帅
Look who's talking.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
还没有
Not just yet.
你改变主意了吗
Have you changed your mind?
没有  没有
No. No.
但我想再跳一支舞
But I would love just one more dance.
探戈
A tango?
还能有什么
What else?
宝贝  应该打包什么
Babe, what should I pack?
只带必需品
Just the essentials.
这个怎么是必需品
How is this essential?
虽然我们是去躲起来
Look, just 'cause we're going into hiding
不代表我们不能打扮好看点
doesn't mean we can't look good.
你看到我的笔记本了吗
Hey, have you seen my laptop?
应该在楼下  看看餐厅桌子上有没有
I think it's downstairs. Check the dining room table.
-好  我马上回  -好的
- Okay, I'll be right back. - All right.
这么说是真的了
So it's true.
你来这做什么
What are you doing here?
我不会待太久的
I won't be here long.
我只想知道为什么
I just want to know why.
现在不是时候  你得离开
Now is not a good time. You have to go.
搞什么
What the hell?
对不起  罗伯
I'm sorry, Rob.
亲爱的  这位是
Honey, this is...
别撒谎了  她知道我们在搞外遇
Don't bother lying. She knows that we were having an affair.
-什么  -求你了
- What? - Please.
-你得走了  -你知道我经常跟你提起
- You have to go! - You know how I always talk to you
我的朋友希拉
about my friend Sheila?
她就是希拉
This is Sheila.
好吧
Uh, okay...
我那天去餐厅是去找你对质的
I came to the diner that day to confront you.
但你人太好了  你说我们可以当朋友
But you were so nice. And you said we could be friends.
等下
Hold on.
你和我的情妇做了朋友
You're friends with my mistress?
是未婚妻
Fiancée.
能晚点再说这个吗
Can we talk about this later?
你都在想什么呢
What could you have been thinking?
你还有脸说话
Oh, you're a fine one to talk.
你已经出轨了几个月
You've been having an affair for months.
一直在计划离开我
You've been planning on leaving me.
天呐  你真的得了癌症吗
Oh, my God. Do you even have cancer?
癌症  你得了癌症
Cancer? You have cancer?
这真是太尴尬了
Well, this is just awkward.
你好
Hi there.
你一定就是贝丝·安了
You must be Beth Ann?
你一定就是萨蒙妮了  请进
You must be Simone. Come in.
-真高兴终于见到你了  -我也是
- It's nice to finally meet you. - Likewise.
我把钥匙放在这附近了
I have the keys around here somewhere.
我找找
Let me look.
我想见你的其中一个原因就是
One of the reasons I wanted to meet
我有个疑问
was because I had a question.
说起来有点尴尬
It's a bit awkward.
你想知道什么
What would you like to know?
房产经纪人告诉我
The realtor told me
有人在这房子里被谋杀了
that someone was murdered in this house?
是真的  我丈夫被杀了
It's true. My husband was killed...
就在你现在所在的位置
right where you're standing.
-天呐  -我们的邻居闯进来
- Oh, dear. - Our neighbor broke in
指责罗伯睡了他老婆
and accused Rob of sleeping with his wife.
开枪把他打死
Shot him dead.
去年被处决了  真可惜
He was executed last year. So sad.
贝丝阿姨  我收拾好了  能走了吗
Aunt Beth, I'm packed. Can we go?
马上  艾尔西  这是萨蒙妮
In a sec. Elsie, this is Simone,
-买了我们房子的女士  -你好
- the woman who bought our house. - Hi, there.
你真漂亮  她是你侄女吗
You're so pretty. She's your niece?
我朋友艾普尔·华纳的女儿
The daughter of my friend, April Warner.
但我从她出生起就开始帮忙照顾她了
But I've been helping take care of her since she was a baby.
艾普尔是歌手  你懂的
April is a singer, you know.
我妈妈会上百老汇
My mom's gonna be on Broadway.
所以我们才卖掉房子  我们要搬去纽约
That's why we sold the house. We're moving to New York.
真令人激动
Oh, how exciting.
这是你的钥匙
Here are your keys.
希望我能在这里过得幸福
I hope to have a very happy life in this house.
幸福生活并不难遇到
A happy life isn't hard to come by.
关键在于不要后悔
The trick is to not regret the choices
你在一路上所作出的选择
you made along the way.
是的
Yes.
那...
Well...
祝你一切顺利
good luck with everything.
你也是  照顾好我的房子
Likewise. Take care of my house.
我会好好爱护它的
I'll give it lots of love.
给
There you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
我相信我们会爱上这里的
I just know that we're gonna love living here.
我希望如此
I certainly hope so.
所以你是什么时候买下这里的
So when did you buy the house?
74年
'74.
但我丈夫去世后  我就把房子租出去了
But after my husband died, I rented the house out.
然后又成了我基金会的总部
Then it was the headquarters for my foundation.
我为艾滋病研究募集资金
I raise money for AIDS research.
我们看过你的报道
Yeah, we've read up on you.
你做出了很多贡献
You've done such amazing work.
在我不再担心钱后
I ended up living a very rich life,
我过上了富裕[丰富多彩]的生活
once I stopped worrying about money.
保罗  我准备好了
Paulo, I'm ready.
那是汤马斯·J·哈特的作品吗
Is that a Thomas J. Harte?
-你知道他的作品  -当然
- Oh, you know his work? - Sure.
我们去年
Yeah, we saw a show of his
-在惠特尼美国艺术博物馆看了他的画展  -是的
- at the Whitney last year. - That's right, yeah.
真好
Oh, isn't that wonderful?
我一直希望汤米能飞黄腾达
I always hoped Tommy would go far.
汤米  他是你朋友吗
Tommy? Is he a friend of yours?
朋友  也可以这么说
A friend? You could say that.
他屁股上文了我的脸
My face is tattooed on his ass.
保罗  推车
Paulo, push.
认识你很开心  泰勒
Well, it's been lovely to meet you, Taylor.
请放心  我和安德鲁
And just know that Andrew and I will
会好好照顾你家的
take wonderful care of your home.
希望你们能住得开心
Aw, well, I hope you'll enjoy it.
我们会的
We will.
我很遗憾你们在这儿的遭遇
And I'm sorry for everything that happened to you here.
不敢想象你们经历了什么
Can't imagine what you went through.
那是可怕的一晚
It was an awful night.
但本可能更糟的
But it could have been worse.
你真的有收藏来复枪
So you really have a rifle collection?
是的  全都在那个箱子里
Yeah. They're all in that box over there.
看看
Hey, check this out.
这是我在非洲狩猎
This is me on safari in Africa.
-瞧瞧  -不是吧
- Look at that. - No way.
我都不知道有喜欢打猎的犹太人
Well, I-I never knew there were Jews that were into hunting.
有的  但对动物来说没那么残忍
We exist. But it's not as cruel to the animals,
因为我们经常射偏
because we miss so frequently.
趁我还没忘
Oh, before I forget,
这是你们的钥匙
here are your keys.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们俩有何打算呢
So, what about the two of you?
找到新的住所了吗
Found a new place to live?
嗯  实际上...
Uh, yeah. Well, actually...
我们准备搬回我们以前的公寓
...we're moving back to our old condo.
在豪宅里生活过后  这可是大退步啊
After living in a mansion. That is some serious downsizing.
对我们来说  其实...
Yeah. For us, it turns out...
少即是多
Less is more.
祝你们好运
Well, best of luck to both of you.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thanks. - Thanks.
他们看上去人不错
They seem like nice people.
昨晚谢谢你
我等不及要再次坐上你的鸡巴了
你会想念这房子吗
Are you gonna miss the house?
就是栋建筑物而已
It's just a building.
居所才是我家所在的地方
Home is where my family is.
已售出
回酒店吗
Back to the hotel?
是的  我准备好做按摩了
Yes. I'm ready for my massage now.
好了  公寓  我们来了
All right. Condo, here we come.
会很不错的  就我们仨
It's gonna be nice. Just the three of us.
亲爱的
Honey?